<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linked data on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/linked-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linked data on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/linked-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RightsStatements.org</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2020/rightsstatements.org/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2020/rightsstatements.org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rightsstatements.org/&#34;&gt;RightsStatements.org&lt;/a&gt; is a consortial initiative that focuses on providing a set of interoperable rights statements that make it easier for people to engage and reuse digital cultural heritage, particularly when provided by metadata aggregators. Since 2014, I have served as the co-chair of the Consortium&amp;rsquo;s Technical Working Group, which is responsible for maintaining the initiative&amp;rsquo;s vocabulary and infrastructure. We maintain our projects on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rightsstatements&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linked Data and Archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2020/linked-data-and-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2020/linked-data-and-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in modeling archival information as linked data since about 2009. Most recently, this includes work with the &lt;abbr name=&#34;Art Libraries Society of North America&#34;&gt;ARLIS/NA&lt;/abbr&gt;, &lt;abbr name=&#34;Rare Books and Manuscrips Section&#34;&gt;RBMS&lt;/abbr&gt;, and &lt;abbr name=&#34;Society of American Archivists&#34;&gt;SAA&lt;/abbr&gt; Joint Task Force on Art and Rare Materials BIBFRAME Ontology Extension. and &lt;a href=&#34;https://archival.github.io/&#34;&gt;Archives and Linked Data Interest Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Support Linked Data</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/why-you-should-support-linked-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/why-you-should-support-linked-data/</guid>
      <description>If you don&#39;t, I&#39;ll make your data linkable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Me A Structured Vocabulary Or I&#39;ll Make One For You</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/make-me-a-structured-vocabulary-or-ill-make-one-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 23:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/make-me-a-structured-vocabulary-or-ill-make-one-for-you/</guid>
      <description>The Society of American Archivists released the Thesaurus for Use in College and University Archives as an electronic publication this week. Specifically, it was issued as a series of PDF files. Is this data stored in some sort of structured format somewhere? If so, it&#39;s not available directly from the SAA site. There&#39;s no good reason why TUCUA shouldn&#39;t be converted to structured, linkable data, expressed using SKOS, the Simple Knowledge Organization System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go FOAF Yourself</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/go-foaf-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 01:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/go-foaf-yourself/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m really looking forward to next week&#39;s code4lib conference in Providence, despite my utter failure to complete or implement the project on which I am presenting. In particular, I&#39;m really looking forward to the linked data preconference. Like some of my other fellow attendees, I&#39;ve hammered out a FOAF file for the preconference already so that Ed Summers&#39; combo FOAF crawler and attendee info web app.

This is what the sample output looks using my FOAF data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>