<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018: a year in gratitude</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/2018-a-year-in-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/2018-a-year-in-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year was largely complicated and often felt like a massive garbage fire to myself and my crew. I didn&amp;rsquo;t accomplish a number of my goals and was &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2018/iterative-intentions-for-2018/&#34;&gt;inconsistent about others&lt;/a&gt;, so recapping awesome things I did doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel appropriate and also happens to be a soft reminder of either failure or things not going as planned. I also tend to hate &amp;ldquo;best of the year&amp;rdquo; lists but I find them helpful to remember about where I found joy or the ability to connect to something outside of myself. I suppose this is an attempt to reconcile those things, or perhaps more in line with the end of year spirit, a way to articulate gratitude to the people and things around me that impacted me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SocketsCDR Audio Zine 3 out soon!</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/socketscdr-audio-zine-3-out-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 17:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/socketscdr-audio-zine-3-out-soon/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m going to be on the latest installment of the SocketsCDR audio zine, curated this time around by Rebecca Mills of The Caution Curves. Sean, the SocketsCDR label honcho, just posted the cover artwork for it and it looks like a great line-up, including friends like The Plums and Stamen &amp;amp; Pistils. This will be my first release in a while (other than the collab CD with myself, Cotton Museum, and Actual Birds on Casanova Temptations).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>