<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drupal on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/drupal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drupal on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 00:46:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/drupal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch Reindexing for Drupal &#43; Solr</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/batch-reindexing-for-drupal-solr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 00:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/batch-reindexing-for-drupal-solr/</guid>
      <description>Crossposted to NYPL Labs. Sorry for any duplication!
Hey, do you use Drupal on a site with several thousand nodes? Do you also use the Apache Solr Integration module? If you&#39;re like me, you&#39;ve probably needed to reindex your site but couldn&#39;t be bothered to wait for those pesky cron runs to finish — in fact, that&#39;s what led me to file a feature request on the module to begin with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal for Archivists: A Drupal-built Archives Reference Blog</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/drupal-for-archivists-a-drupal-built-archives-reference-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 22:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/drupal-for-archivists-a-drupal-built-archives-reference-blog/</guid>
      <description>When Mark asked me to write about our use of Drupal at the Dickinson College Archives and Special Collections, the first thing I thought about was when our Archives Reference Blog was initially launched in April 2007. I couldn&#39;t believe that it has been two years already. I am pleased to report that my colleagues at Dickinson and I are enormously happy with the results of those two years. I hope others may find this brief explanation of how and why we are using Drupal as a reference management tool to be helpful and instructive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon: Drupal for Archivists</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/coming-soon-drupal-for-archivists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 22:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/coming-soon-drupal-for-archivists/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been fairly quiet lately as I&#39;ve been busy with this and that, but I thought I&#39;d let everyone know that I&#39;ve been beginning to put together a series of posts entitled &#34;Drupal for Archivists.&#34; Drupal, as you may or may not know, is a flexible and extensible open source content management system. There will be a general overview of some of the important concepts, but it&#39;ll focus less on the basics of getting people up and running — there are plenty of resources out there, such as the wonderful tutorials and articles available from Lullabot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightening the load: Drupal and Python</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/lightening-the-load-drupal-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 01:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/lightening-the-load-drupal-and-python/</guid>
      <description>{% include youtube.html id=&#34;Mv7j-ZYULas&#34; %}
Man, if this isn&#39;t a &#34;you got your peanut butter in my chocolate thing&#34; or what! As I wrote over on the NYPL Labs blog, we&#39;ve been up to our necks in Drupal at MPOW, and I&#39;ve found that one of the great advantages of using it is rapid prototyping without having to write a whole lot of code. Again, that&#39;s how I feel about Python, too, but you knew that already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Old is New Again</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/everything-old-is-new-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/everything-old-is-new-again/</guid>
      <description>Goodbye, WordPress - I&#39;ve been drinking more of the KoolAid. I rebuilt my personal/professional site (not this blog) in Drupal. Migrating the content was pretty easy (about 15 static pages, no posts). The functionality is astounding - I only started working on redoing it yesterday and I&#39;ve already got a great infrastructure. Expect a detailed post before too long, or at least a link to a colophon on said site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>