<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Library 2.0 on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/library-2.0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Library 2.0 on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 11:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/library-2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>V8-Powered Libraries and the Happiness Engines that Run Them</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/v8-powered-libraries-and-the-happiness-engines-that-run-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/v8-powered-libraries-and-the-happiness-engines-that-run-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously posted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.nypl.org&#34;&gt;http://labs.nypl.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Games we used to play / writte... Digital ID: 1255304. New York Public Library&#34; href=&#34;http://digitalgallery.nypl.org/nypldigital/id?1255304&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://matienzo.org/images/1255304.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Games we used to play / writte... Digital ID: 1255304. New York Public Library&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week ago today, a few of my &lt;abbr title=&#34;Digital Experience Group&#34;&gt;DEG&lt;/abbr&gt; colleagues and I went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://mamamusings.net/&#34;&gt;Liz Lawley&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;abbr title=&#34;Rochester Institute of Technology&#34;&gt;RIT&lt;/abbr&gt;&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://social.it.rit.edu/&#34;&gt;Lab for Social Computing&lt;/a&gt; give a talk entitled &#34;Libraries as Happiness Engines.&#34; It was a modified version of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shushers.ca/cil2008/?p=14&#34;&gt;talk she gave at this year&#39;s &lt;abbr title=&#34;Computers in Libraries&#34;&gt;CiL&lt;/abbr&gt; conference&lt;/a&gt;. The gist of the talk was that &lt;a href=&#34;http://gaming.ala.org/&#34;&gt;gaming in libraries&lt;/a&gt; means not just using established games to draw the public into the library, but also to begin implementing game mechanics into libraries that allow them to flourish as social spaces. In particular, these game mechanics include things like collecting, points, feedback, exchanges, and customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been ruminating on this for the last week or so in a couple different ways. First of all, I&#39;ve been trying to figure out how we could implement game mechanics within NYPL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0, Disaster, and Archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/web-2.0-disaster-and-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 01:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/web-2.0-disaster-and-archives/</guid>
      <description>Many of Web 2.0&#39;s detractors argue about it&#39;s real value, but given the wildfires in Southern California, I was happy to see it really put to good use. KPBS, a San Diego radio station, has been using Flickr and, even more shocking (at least for some), Twitter as ways to disseminate information and news quickly. The use of Twitter is particularly interesting as it can send out SMS messages. You might recall a few years ago when protesters in the Philippines used SMS to organize political rallies and warn of police retaliation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives Camp: Talking About Archives 2.0</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/archives-camp-talking-about-archives-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 15:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/archives-camp-talking-about-archives-2.0/</guid>
      <description>ArchivesNext recently discussed the possibility of having some &#34;Archives 2.0&#34;-themed events this summer, and I think it&#39;s a great idea. Now, we may not be able to throw something together in time for SAA, but it seems like the idea of at least meeting up informally is percolating. There&#39;s a wealth of opportunities available for archives and archivists to improve access to their holdings through social software and the like. My vision, as I said in a comment on the post, would be to end up with an unconference along the lines of a Library Camp (or more generally, a BarCamp), maybe with lightning talks if enough of us have something to show off or talk about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>