<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronic Records on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/electronic-records/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Electronic Records on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/electronic-records/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Born digital archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2013/born-digital-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2013/born-digital-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my past life, I worked as a digital archivist, focusing on managing born digital collections. Links to some of the past projects I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in follow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration Before Preservation: Recovering Born Digital Records in the Stephen Gendin Papers</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2013/collaboration-before-preservation-recovering-born-digital-records-in-the-stephen-gendin-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2013/collaboration-before-preservation-recovering-born-digital-records-in-the-stephen-gendin-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some, the phrase &amp;ldquo;born digital resources&amp;rdquo; may be unfamiliar, but Ricky Erway, Senior Program Officer at OCLC Research wrote a brief essay entitled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oclc.org/content/dam/research/activities/hiddencollections/borndigital.pdf?urlm=161291&#34;&gt;Defining &amp;ldquo;Born Digital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a handy, working definition: &amp;ldquo;items created and managed in digital form.&amp;rdquo; Manuscripts and Archives, the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, and Yale University Library overall have had a notable history of working with born digital resources over the past ten years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Hours: The Day of Digital Archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/24-hours-the-day-of-digital-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 10:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/24-hours-the-day-of-digital-archives/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, October 6 was the Day of Digital Archives, organized by friend and colleague Gretchen Gueguen at the University of Virginia. I missed the post deadline yesterday, but it&#39;s been a busy week, so I might as well walk through some of the highlights of my work related to digital archives that occurred during that 24 hours from 12 am Thursday to 12 am Friday.
12 AM: It&#39;s late, but I&#39;m finishing the last bit of work of writing up lecture notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delicious and the Preservation of &#34;Platforms&#34;</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/delicious-and-the-preservation-of-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 23:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/delicious-and-the-preservation-of-platforms/</guid>
      <description>Just as plenty of others have, I recoiled in horror when I heard that Delicious (née del.icio.us) was being &#34;sunsetted&#34;. Regardless of the red flags that have been raised about its potentially imminent demise, I&#39;ve still been using it on a daily basis. I&#39;ve been an active user for over 6.5 years, which is longer than I can say for just about any other web platform or service. I deleted my Friendster and Myspace accounts quite a while ago; I&#39;ve been on Flickr almost as long as Delicious, but the bookmarking wins out by a good four months or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Aus-Archivists Not Dead?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/update-aus-archivists-not-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 08:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/update-aus-archivists-not-dead/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today I&#39;d posted about the Australian Society of Archivists&#39; announcement about the Aus-Archivists listserv being &#34;lost.&#34; Tim Sherratt, an Australian colleague and friend of this blog, announced this post on ArchivesLive, the Ning group created by the ASA seemingly to replace the listserv. Pat Jackson, ASA President, has already responded with an update:
The ASA National Office has not lost the Aus-Archivists list-serv. We have moved from an outsourced service provider to managing our new server at the National Office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Aus-Archivists: Listservs and the Commitment to Digital Preservation</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/goodbye-aus-archivists-listservs-and-the-commitment-to-digital-preservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 02:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/goodbye-aus-archivists-listservs-and-the-commitment-to-digital-preservation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Aus-Archivists might not be gone for good, as ASA intends to share the entire run of postings on its website. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2010/aus-archivists-listserv-update/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for details.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my relative &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2010/giving-up-on-a-and-a/&#34;&gt;distaste for the A&amp;amp;A list&lt;/a&gt;, I have previously found it useful and &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2007/saa-listserv/&#34;&gt;argued for its retention&lt;/a&gt; when it was threatened in 2007. I still agree with most of what I wrote 3.5 years ago, although I might have toned things down in retrospect. In an effort to find other e-mail discussion lists on archives that engaged my interest, I joined &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mailman.srv.ualberta.ca/mailman/listinfo/arcan-l&#34;&gt;Arcan-L&lt;/a&gt; (the Canadian archivists&#39; listserv) and Aus-Archivists (the Australian archivists&#39; listserv, maintained by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archivists.org.au/&#34;&gt;Australian Society of Archivists&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, Aus-Archivists had been idle since around the end of October. I noticed &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ausarchivists/status/29524056111&#34;&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt; from the Australian Society of Archivists only in passing at the beginning of November:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ASA Office would just like everyone to know that our List Serv is still currently unavailable, we apologize for any inconvenience...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t hear anything else between then and earlier today. I should note that I&#39;m not a member of ASA, and so I can&#39;t speak to any communication they had with their membership. However, today a message was sent out by Pat Jackson, the ASA President, to all Aus-Archivists subscribers, announcing that the listserv was lost entirely. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Medium Is Not The Message</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/the-medium-is-not-the-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 12:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/the-medium-is-not-the-message/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Electronic records&#34; is a particularly awful phrase and does not even actually capture anything about the underlying records at all. As far as the term goes, it&#39;s not too far off from &#34;machine readable records.&#34; As a profession, can we start actually thinking critically about the underlying technical issues and push for using terms that more accurately describe what it is we&#39;re dealing with? I understand it&#39;s a convenient catch-all term, but there is a large range of issues that differ with the kinds of data and systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Message Discovery</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/google-message-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 13:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/google-message-discovery/</guid>
      <description>Amidst this week of notorious hoaxes, Google has launched Google Message Discovery as an enterprise-focused add on for its Google Apps platform. Google Message Discovery goes well beyond a simple and reliable e-mail backup system and provides three key features of interest to records managers:
 Content-addressable storage for electronic mail stored immediately upon sending or retrieval Creating explicit retention policies based upon time Compliance with relevant laws and best practices Straightforward discovery for any use, regardless if internal or concerning litigation  Google Message Discovery, as well as other related offerings such as e-mail security, clearly has its origins in Google&#39;s acquisition of Postini last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataPortability.org and the Dream of a Web 2.0 Backup System</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/dataportability.org-and-the-dream-of-a-web-2.0-backup-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 20:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/dataportability.org-and-the-dream-of-a-web-2.0-backup-system/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered DataPortability.org through Peter Van Garderen&#39;s blog post about it. I was entirely surprised that I&#39;d heard nary a peep about it. Some basic examination (running a WHOIS query on the domain) shows that it&#39;s still a fairly new project. I have to say, though, that I&#39;m entirely impressed. Those involved have given a whole lot of thought to how they&#39;re going to be doing things, as evidenced by those who have signed up to be involved and the DataPortability Charter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throwing Out the Baby, the Bathwater, and the Bathtub: The Sad State of the Archives and Archivists Listserv</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/throwing-out-the-baby-the-bathwater-and-the-bathtub-the-sad-state-of-the-archives-and-archivists-listserv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 23:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/throwing-out-the-baby-the-bathwater-and-the-bathtub-the-sad-state-of-the-archives-and-archivists-listserv/</guid>
      <description>Today, Nancy Beaumont, Executive Director of the Society of American Archivists, made an announcement on the Archives &amp;amp; Archivists listserv that SAA would no longer retain the first thirteen years of posts from the listserv. During this time the listserv was hosted by Miami University of Ohio, and last September, the list was moved to an SAA server. This stems from a decision made by SAA Council that they not retain the archives for three reasons: 1) an appraisal decision informed by the SAA&#39;s archives at the University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee, 2) a consideration of administrative issues, and 3) a consideration of cost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>