<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Site News on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/site-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Site News on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 17:02:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/site-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs news: Disappearing Blogspot Blogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-news-disappearing-blogspot-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-news-disappearing-blogspot-blogs/</guid>
      <description>ArchivesBlogs has been going strong for over a week now. If you use Blogspot and had a blog previously syndicated by ArchivesBlogs, your content may be temporarily unsyndicated. The specific problem is HTTP 502 error, which seems to indicate a problem with a proxy server at Blogspot. In any rate, they should return soon enough -- it would be nice to have the 9 blogs back!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syndicating archives blogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/syndicating-archives-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 16:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/syndicating-archives-blogs/</guid>
      <description>I still haven&#39;t had enough time to process everything I took in or ideas I came up with as a result of the SAA conference. Many were more diligent than I and I&#39;m sorry to say I didn&#39;t meet them, but some highlights follow:
 Geof Huth took notes on the SAA Awards Ceremony, Christie Peterson pitted Archon against Archivist&#39;s Toolkit, Jessamyn West blogged about her session on blogs, Peter Van Garderen discusses his experience at the conference including his session on archives and Web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change of Platform</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/change-of-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 15:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/change-of-platform/</guid>
      <description>Nearly a year ago I switched from Wordpress to Drupal. I chose to switch back, partially because it was capable of doing way more than I needed it to! I thought I didn&#39;t want to be limited by blog software, but apparently that&#39;s not a terribly huge concern anymore. The old site had frightfully little content (three posts in Dalliance, a few personal posts, and links to papers). I&#39;m redoing my non-blog site with PURLs since I don&#39;t have access to an e-prints server to which I can upload my varied previous academic work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>