<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 23:04:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sumer Is Icumen In</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/sumer-is-icumen-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 23:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/sumer-is-icumen-in/</guid>
      <description>I have spent the last several months in a fog. Emotions tend to get the better of me whenever faced with a barrier in my work life. It&#39;s gotten increasingly difficult for me to see the forest for the trees, no matter how much I tell myself that my work is for the greater good of my unit, my institution, and archivy. Self-doubt creeps in, as does stress, frustration, depression. Positivity begins to wane, with optimism replaced by apathy and sarcasm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Memoriam: Robert Frost, 1952-2011</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/in-memoriam-robert-frost-1952-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 08:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/in-memoriam-robert-frost-1952-2011/</guid>
      <description>I am sad to announce the passing of Robert L. &#34;Bob&#34; Frost (1952-2011). Bob was an associate professor at the University of Michigan School of Information, my alma mater, where he had taught since 2000. Bob had been battling cancer for over two years. Ed Vielmetti has written an obituary of Bob on his blog, including the announcement from SI Dean Jeffrey Mackie-Mason.
Bob was an inspiration to many of us SI alums, and his magnetic personality, sharp wit, and joie de vivre ensured he had a bevy of his students and colleagues buzzing around him at any given time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onward And Upward...</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/onward-and-upward.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 02:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/onward-and-upward.../</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s fitting that this the hundredth (gosh, only the hundredth?) post, because I have rather important news. First, my fellow developers/producers/UX designers at The New York Public Library and I have been dealing with every minute detail on the upcoming, Drupal-based replacement to the NYPL website. You can see a live preview at http://new.nypl.org/. I can proudly say that this project has helped both me personally and NYPL overall play nice in the open source world - we&#39;ve been actively contributing code, reporting bugs, and sending patches to the Drupal project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is All I&#39;m Going To Say On This Here Blogsite Concerning The Brouhaha About The Policy for Use and Transfer of WorldCat Records Because I Have Other, More Interesting And More Complex Problems To Solve (And So Do You)</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/this-is-all-im-going-to-say-on-this-here-blogsite-concerning-the-brouhaha-about-the-policy-for-use-and-transfer-of-worldcat-records-because-i-have-other-more-interesting-and-more-complex-problems-to-solve-and-so-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2009 03:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/this-is-all-im-going-to-say-on-this-here-blogsite-concerning-the-brouhaha-about-the-policy-for-use-and-transfer-of-worldcat-records-because-i-have-other-more-interesting-and-more-complex-problems-to-solve-and-so-do-you/</guid>
      <description>The moderated discussion hosted and sponsored by Nylink went pretty well. Also, I don&#39;t need the records to have fun with the data &#34;” I just need robust APIs. (In fact, as I said today, I&#39;d prefer not to have to deal with the MARC records directly.) Robust APIs would help making prototypes like this one I hacked together in a few hours into a real, usable service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Old is New Again</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/everything-old-is-new-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/everything-old-is-new-again/</guid>
      <description>Goodbye, WordPress - I&#39;ve been drinking more of the KoolAid. I rebuilt my personal/professional site (not this blog) in Drupal. Migrating the content was pretty easy (about 15 static pages, no posts). The functionality is astounding - I only started working on redoing it yesterday and I&#39;ve already got a great infrastructure. Expect a detailed post before too long, or at least a link to a colophon on said site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now, It Can Be Told</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/now-it-can-be-told/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 16:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/now-it-can-be-told/</guid>
      <description>After a little over two years processing, referencing, and cataloging, and hacking at AIP, I&#39;m skipping up to the City That Never Sleeps to join Jay Datema, Josh Greenberg, and company in the NYPL Labs. I&#39;d be lying if I said I wasn&#39;t thrilled about this opportunity, and I&#39;m ready to see where my new job will take me. The next major hurdle will be finding a place to live, so if you&#39;re privy to anything in Brooklyn, please let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticking My Neck Out</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/sticking-my-neck-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 16:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/sticking-my-neck-out/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been some time since I&#39;ve had a substantive post, and I don&#39;t really intend to write one now. I figured I should mention, however, that I&#39;ve been featured lately in print and in the blogosphere. Jessamyn West of librarian.net interviewed me for an article (&#34;Saving Digital History&#34;) in Library Journal netConnect. In addition, I was tapped by the wonderful folks at Booktruck for the latest installment in their &#34;Ask a Male Librarian&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Non-Library Blogs I Read</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/five-non-library-blogs-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2007 14:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/five-non-library-blogs-i-read/</guid>
      <description>I won&#39;t bother waiting to be tagged to do this, because all the cool kids already are. I read too many blogs already, so here we go.
 Mary Eats is, as one would easily assume, a blog about food. Mary started the blog while she and her husband were living in Korea, and thus there&#39;s an overwhelming emphasis on Korean food and restaurants. She moved to Seattle relatively recently and began culinary school, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braindump</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/braindump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 18:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/braindump/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m really behind on posting, and I apologize. There are a few action items that I should mention before I clear my brain to allow me to start posting things with actual content.
 ArchivesBlogs moved, but mail to archivesblogs.com was not working for a while. A few people mentioned this to me, but I didn&#39;t get this resolved until just last week. After who knows how many attempts trying to get something posted on Boing Boing, I finally made it when I had more information about the hottest chili peppers in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs update: service links</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-update-service-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2006 16:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-update-service-links/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve upgraded Plagger (the software behind ArchivesBlogs) to the latest version and it&#39;s allowed me to add service links to del.icio.us, unalog, digg, Reddit, and Technorati. I suppose I could add more (ma.gnolia, Furl, etc.), but I&#39;ll hold off doing that for the sake of cluttering the interface for the time being. If you have any service links you&#39;d like to see, let me know and I might be able to hack something together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report from SAA: Archival Solidarity and International Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/report-from-saa-archival-solidarity-and-international-cooperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 16:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/report-from-saa-archival-solidarity-and-international-cooperation/</guid>
      <description>The Archival Solidarity Session was really great and generated a lot of dialog. It was originally organized by Nancy Marrelli of Concordia University (Montréal), but she couldn&#39;t make it on account of a family emergency. Trudy Huskamp Peterson led the discussion in her place and did a wonderful job. Essentially, Archival Solidarity is a project involving the ICA&#39;s Section of Professional Associations that concerns &#34;international archival development&#34; through bilateral projects. There are several major issues at play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-November 2005 updates: Dalliance off the ground! Site changes galore! DC Not Bad!</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2005/mid-november-2005-updates-dalliance-off-the-ground-site-changes-galore-dc-not-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2005 00:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2005/mid-november-2005-updates-dalliance-off-the-ground-site-changes-galore-dc-not-bad/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve finally gotten around to doing some serious work on the site. I&#39;ve completed the first post for my defunct blog, and it&#39;s about one of my favorite songwriters ever, Dr. Franklin Bruno. I&#39;ve also figured out some of the odd intricacies of Drupal and am finally getting this site to have a look and feel of which I can be proud.
I&#39;ve settled in nicely to Washington, DC, and I&#39;m living in a decent area of town within a reasonable interest of a decent watering hole, groceries, and the Metro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off on my way: in transition to Washington, DC</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2005/off-on-my-way-in-transition-to-washington-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 23:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2005/off-on-my-way-in-transition-to-washington-dc/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m pleased to announce that I will be joining the staff of the National Anthropological Archives and Human Studies Film Archives of the Smithsonian Institution&#39;s Department of Anthropology as a project archivist. I will have two initial primary responsibilities:
 cataloging Plains Indian ledger art for the non-profit ARTstor Project, and original cataloging and bibliographic enhancement of audio, film and video collections in support of the NAA&#39;s new Endangered Languages Program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>