<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archives on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/archives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archives on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/archives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linked Data and Archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2020/linked-data-and-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2020/linked-data-and-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in modeling archival information as linked data since about 2009. Most recently, this includes work with the &lt;abbr name=&#34;Art Libraries Society of North America&#34;&gt;ARLIS/NA&lt;/abbr&gt;, &lt;abbr name=&#34;Rare Books and Manuscrips Section&#34;&gt;RBMS&lt;/abbr&gt;, and &lt;abbr name=&#34;Society of American Archivists&#34;&gt;SAA&lt;/abbr&gt; Joint Task Force on Art and Rare Materials BIBFRAME Ontology Extension. and &lt;a href=&#34;https://archival.github.io/&#34;&gt;Archives and Linked Data Interest Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments on revisions to SAA statement on Diversity and Inclusion</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2020/comments-on-revisions-to-saa-statement-on-diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2020/comments-on-revisions-to-saa-statement-on-diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title=&#34;Society of American Archivists&#34;&gt;SAA&lt;/abbr&gt; Council has issued a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.archivists.org/news/2020/call-for-member-comments-saa-statement-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion&#34;&gt;call for comments&lt;/a&gt; on the SAA Statement on Diversity and Inclusion. As noted in the announcement, the revision includes changes to expand the statement to cover equity as well. Comments are open on the revisions until March 12, 2020, and what follows are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.archivists.org/news/2020/call-for-member-comments-saa-statement-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion#comment-540&#34;&gt;comments that I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018: a year in gratitude</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/2018-a-year-in-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/2018-a-year-in-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year was largely complicated and often felt like a massive garbage fire to myself and my crew. I didn&amp;rsquo;t accomplish a number of my goals and was &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2018/iterative-intentions-for-2018/&#34;&gt;inconsistent about others&lt;/a&gt;, so recapping awesome things I did doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel appropriate and also happens to be a soft reminder of either failure or things not going as planned. I also tend to hate &amp;ldquo;best of the year&amp;rdquo; lists but I find them helpful to remember about where I found joy or the ability to connect to something outside of myself. I suppose this is an attempt to reconcile those things, or perhaps more in line with the end of year spirit, a way to articulate gratitude to the people and things around me that impacted me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesSpace</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2013/archivesspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2013/archivesspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archivesspace.org&#34;&gt;ArchivesSpace&lt;/a&gt; is an open source archival management system. During the project&amp;rsquo;s grant-funded phases in 2010-2013, I worked as a technical consultant during the planning phase, and as Technical Architect and product owner during the implementation phase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Born digital archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2013/born-digital-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2013/born-digital-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my past life, I worked as a digital archivist, focusing on managing born digital collections. Links to some of the past projects I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in follow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration Before Preservation: Recovering Born Digital Records in the Stephen Gendin Papers</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2013/collaboration-before-preservation-recovering-born-digital-records-in-the-stephen-gendin-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2013/collaboration-before-preservation-recovering-born-digital-records-in-the-stephen-gendin-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some, the phrase &amp;ldquo;born digital resources&amp;rdquo; may be unfamiliar, but Ricky Erway, Senior Program Officer at OCLC Research wrote a brief essay entitled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oclc.org/content/dam/research/activities/hiddencollections/borndigital.pdf?urlm=161291&#34;&gt;Defining &amp;ldquo;Born Digital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a handy, working definition: &amp;ldquo;items created and managed in digital form.&amp;rdquo; Manuscripts and Archives, the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, and Yale University Library overall have had a notable history of working with born digital resources over the past ten years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Hours: The Day of Digital Archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/24-hours-the-day-of-digital-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 10:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/24-hours-the-day-of-digital-archives/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, October 6 was the Day of Digital Archives, organized by friend and colleague Gretchen Gueguen at the University of Virginia. I missed the post deadline yesterday, but it&#39;s been a busy week, so I might as well walk through some of the highlights of my work related to digital archives that occurred during that 24 hours from 12 am Thursday to 12 am Friday.
12 AM: It&#39;s late, but I&#39;m finishing the last bit of work of writing up lecture notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Aus-Archivists Not Dead?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/update-aus-archivists-not-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 08:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/update-aus-archivists-not-dead/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today I&#39;d posted about the Australian Society of Archivists&#39; announcement about the Aus-Archivists listserv being &#34;lost.&#34; Tim Sherratt, an Australian colleague and friend of this blog, announced this post on ArchivesLive, the Ning group created by the ASA seemingly to replace the listserv. Pat Jackson, ASA President, has already responded with an update:
The ASA National Office has not lost the Aus-Archivists list-serv. We have moved from an outsourced service provider to managing our new server at the National Office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Aus-Archivists: Listservs and the Commitment to Digital Preservation</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/goodbye-aus-archivists-listservs-and-the-commitment-to-digital-preservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 02:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/goodbye-aus-archivists-listservs-and-the-commitment-to-digital-preservation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Aus-Archivists might not be gone for good, as ASA intends to share the entire run of postings on its website. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2010/aus-archivists-listserv-update/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for details.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my relative &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2010/giving-up-on-a-and-a/&#34;&gt;distaste for the A&amp;amp;A list&lt;/a&gt;, I have previously found it useful and &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2007/saa-listserv/&#34;&gt;argued for its retention&lt;/a&gt; when it was threatened in 2007. I still agree with most of what I wrote 3.5 years ago, although I might have toned things down in retrospect. In an effort to find other e-mail discussion lists on archives that engaged my interest, I joined &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mailman.srv.ualberta.ca/mailman/listinfo/arcan-l&#34;&gt;Arcan-L&lt;/a&gt; (the Canadian archivists&#39; listserv) and Aus-Archivists (the Australian archivists&#39; listserv, maintained by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archivists.org.au/&#34;&gt;Australian Society of Archivists&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, Aus-Archivists had been idle since around the end of October. I noticed &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ausarchivists/status/29524056111&#34;&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt; from the Australian Society of Archivists only in passing at the beginning of November:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ASA Office would just like everyone to know that our List Serv is still currently unavailable, we apologize for any inconvenience...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t hear anything else between then and earlier today. I should note that I&#39;m not a member of ASA, and so I can&#39;t speak to any communication they had with their membership. However, today a message was sent out by Pat Jackson, the ASA President, to all Aus-Archivists subscribers, announcing that the listserv was lost entirely. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Have Given Up On the Archives and Archivists List</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/why-i-have-given-up-on-the-archives-and-archivists-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 19:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/why-i-have-given-up-on-the-archives-and-archivists-list/</guid>
      <description>I am certainly not the first person to chime in on this topic, and I certainly hope not to be the last. Inspired by two fantastic posts by Ben Bromley and Maureen Callahan, I have chosen to discuss the reasons why I have given up on the Archives and Archivists List. Unlike Ben and Maureen, who discuss why they choose not to post to the list, I&#39;m also including reasons why I choose not to read or subscribe to the list anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bird&#39;s Eye View of Archival Collections</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/a-birds-eye-view-of-archival-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 01:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/a-birds-eye-view-of-archival-collections/</guid>
      <description>Mitchell Whitelaw is a Senior Lecturer in the Faculty of Design and Creative Practice at the University of Canberra and the 2008 winner of the National Archives of Australia&#39;s Ian Maclean Award. According to the NAA&#39;s site, the Ian Maclean Award commemorates archivist Ian Maclean, and is awarded
to individuals interested in conducting research that will benefit the archival and historical profession in Australia and promote the important contribution that archives make to society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad MARC Rant #1: Leader Positions 06 and 08</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/bad-marc-rant-#1-leader-positions-06-and-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 13:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/bad-marc-rant-#1-leader-positions-06-and-08/</guid>
      <description>I understand why the MARC leader position 08 is a good idea in theory. In fact, MARBI Proposal 97-07 suggests:
a change in definition to Leader/08 code &#34;a&#34; for clarification; making code &#34;t&#34; (Manuscript language materials) obsolete in Leader/06 and using code &#34;a&#34; instead; redefinitions of codes &#34;a&#34; and &#34;p&#34; in Leader/06; renaming the 008 for Books to &#34;Textual (Nonserial); and deleting field 006 for Mixed material.
 I can safely say that some pretty funky stuff gets cataloged with the leader position 08 set as &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seriously, Follow Our Lead</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/seriously-follow-our-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 15:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/seriously-follow-our-lead/</guid>
      <description>OCLC&#39;s Lorcan Dempsey makes a great point as usual in his post &#34;Making tracks&#34;:
In recent presentations, I have been suggesting that libraries will need to adopt more archival skills as they manage digital collections and think about provenance, evidential integrity, and context, and that they will also need to adopt more museum perspectives as they think about how their digital collections work as educational resources, and consider exhibitions and interpretive environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICA Releases International Standard for Describing Functions</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/ica-releases-international-standard-for-describing-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/ica-releases-international-standard-for-describing-functions/</guid>
      <description>The ICA&#39;s Committee of Best Practices and Standards released the first edition of the International Standard for Describing Functions (ISDF). Like much of ICA&#39;s other work in descriptive standards for archives, ISDF is designed to be used in conjunction with established standards such as ISAD(G) and ISAAR(CPF), as well as standards in preparation such as ISIAH. ISDF will assist both archivists and users to understand the contextual aspects of the creation of records of corporate bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movin&#39; and shakin&#39; in the archives world</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/movin-and-shakin-in-the-archives-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 12:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/movin-and-shakin-in-the-archives-world/</guid>
      <description>ArchivesNext recently discussed Library Journal&#39;s annual list of &#34;Movers and Shakers,&#34; pondering what a comparable list in the archival profession would look like. For those who don&#39;t know, the list recognizes &#34;library advocates, community builders, 2.0 gurus, innovators, marketers, mentors, and problem solvers transforming libraries.&#34; After some rumination, ArchivesNext is now calling for nominations to generate a similar list. Do your civic duty and nominate either a project, an individual, or even a situation worthy of this recognition!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataPortability.org and the Dream of a Web 2.0 Backup System</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/dataportability.org-and-the-dream-of-a-web-2.0-backup-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 20:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/dataportability.org-and-the-dream-of-a-web-2.0-backup-system/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered DataPortability.org through Peter Van Garderen&#39;s blog post about it. I was entirely surprised that I&#39;d heard nary a peep about it. Some basic examination (running a WHOIS query on the domain) shows that it&#39;s still a fairly new project. I have to say, though, that I&#39;m entirely impressed. Those involved have given a whole lot of thought to how they&#39;re going to be doing things, as evidenced by those who have signed up to be involved and the DataPortability Charter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0, Disaster, and Archives</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/web-2.0-disaster-and-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 01:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/web-2.0-disaster-and-archives/</guid>
      <description>Many of Web 2.0&#39;s detractors argue about it&#39;s real value, but given the wildfires in Southern California, I was happy to see it really put to good use. KPBS, a San Diego radio station, has been using Flickr and, even more shocking (at least for some), Twitter as ways to disseminate information and news quickly. The use of Twitter is particularly interesting as it can send out SMS messages. You might recall a few years ago when protesters in the Philippines used SMS to organize political rallies and warn of police retaliation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives Camp: Talking About Archives 2.0</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/archives-camp-talking-about-archives-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 15:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/archives-camp-talking-about-archives-2.0/</guid>
      <description>ArchivesNext recently discussed the possibility of having some &#34;Archives 2.0&#34;-themed events this summer, and I think it&#39;s a great idea. Now, we may not be able to throw something together in time for SAA, but it seems like the idea of at least meeting up informally is percolating. There&#39;s a wealth of opportunities available for archives and archivists to improve access to their holdings through social software and the like. My vision, as I said in a comment on the post, would be to end up with an unconference along the lines of a Library Camp (or more generally, a BarCamp), maybe with lightning talks if enough of us have something to show off or talk about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NARA Frees Their Data, Somewhat</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/nara-frees-their-data-somewhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2007 12:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/nara-frees-their-data-somewhat/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a bit surprised that this hasn&#39;t come across anyone&#39;s radar, because it seems awfully damn significant to me. According to this post on the A&amp;amp;A listserv by Michael Ravnitzky, the National Archives and Records Administration released an exhaustive database of box holdings of all the Federal Records Centers. He doesn&#39;t really say how he obtained this database, but my guess is he just asked based upon his background and interest in public access to government information - I&#39;ve come across his name on material relating to FOIA before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticking My Neck Out</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/sticking-my-neck-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 16:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/sticking-my-neck-out/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been some time since I&#39;ve had a substantive post, and I don&#39;t really intend to write one now. I figured I should mention, however, that I&#39;ve been featured lately in print and in the blogosphere. Jessamyn West of librarian.net interviewed me for an article (&#34;Saving Digital History&#34;) in Library Journal netConnect. In addition, I was tapped by the wonderful folks at Booktruck for the latest installment in their &#34;Ask a Male Librarian&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protection From Human Pests</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/protection-from-human-pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2007 17:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/protection-from-human-pests/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago (while I was at NACO training) I got a reader&#39;s card at the Library of Congress. For a while I pretty actively went and requested books on Saturday afternoons. In particular, I was interested in archival manuals from outside the United States. One of the most interesting books I found was S. M. Jaffar&#39;s Problems of an Archivist, a manual written in Pakistan in 1948. I was struck by the following passage (&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Work-Safe Tidbits about Archives and Erotica</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/two-work-safe-tidbits-about-archives-and-erotica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 14:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/two-work-safe-tidbits-about-archives-and-erotica/</guid>
      <description>First, via my associates at booktruck.org, I came across a review of the comic book Demonslayer v. 2.2, by a certain Marat Mychaels, et al. at Comics Should Be Good. While the fact that the reviewers pan the comic book seems only marginally of interest to those of us wading in archivy, I should draw your attention to a specific part of this issue. Apparently one of the characters goes to visit the Director of Archives at the New York Museum of Natural History, who has chosen to decorate his office in the style of some seemingly life-sized works by (fellow Peruvian) Boris Vallejo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throwing Out the Baby, the Bathwater, and the Bathtub: The Sad State of the Archives and Archivists Listserv</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/throwing-out-the-baby-the-bathwater-and-the-bathtub-the-sad-state-of-the-archives-and-archivists-listserv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 23:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/throwing-out-the-baby-the-bathwater-and-the-bathtub-the-sad-state-of-the-archives-and-archivists-listserv/</guid>
      <description>Today, Nancy Beaumont, Executive Director of the Society of American Archivists, made an announcement on the Archives &amp;amp; Archivists listserv that SAA would no longer retain the first thirteen years of posts from the listserv. During this time the listserv was hosted by Miami University of Ohio, and last September, the list was moved to an SAA server. This stems from a decision made by SAA Council that they not retain the archives for three reasons: 1) an appraisal decision informed by the SAA&#39;s archives at the University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee, 2) a consideration of administrative issues, and 3) a consideration of cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Open Source Archival Management Software</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/the-state-of-open-source-archival-management-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/the-state-of-open-source-archival-management-software/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve written here, but other responsibilities at both at home and work have kept me busy. To get back into the swing of writing regularly, I thought I&#39;d take a look at one of the biggest hot-button topics in archives this year: the development and release of open source archival management systems. Between this year&#39;s and last year&#39;s SAA conferences, there were three sessions that, at least in part, dealt with the development of open source software for archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ArchivesBlogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/announcing-archivesblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2006 10:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/announcing-archivesblogs/</guid>
      <description>Since my last post about syndicating blogs about archives, I&#39;ve played around with the idea and different software packages to do it, including Planet and Plagger. I&#39;m happy to announce that after a few days work I was able to put something together.
ArchivesBlogs is an aggregator for blogs about archives. It runs Plagger and updates hourly, outputting HTML, RSS, Atom, OPML (for import into other aggregator), and a FOAFroll. The site design is simple, but i&#39;m happy with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syndicating archives blogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/syndicating-archives-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 16:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/syndicating-archives-blogs/</guid>
      <description>I still haven&#39;t had enough time to process everything I took in or ideas I came up with as a result of the SAA conference. Many were more diligent than I and I&#39;m sorry to say I didn&#39;t meet them, but some highlights follow:
 Geof Huth took notes on the SAA Awards Ceremony, Christie Peterson pitted Archon against Archivist&#39;s Toolkit, Jessamyn West blogged about her session on blogs, Peter Van Garderen discusses his experience at the conference including his session on archives and Web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>