<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>to read on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/to-read/</link>
    <description>Recent content in to read on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 17:34:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/to-read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>thorpe</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/24/thorpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 17:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/24/thorpe/</guid>
      <description>This article explores questions regarding the development and support of Indigenous priorities and self-determination in Australian libraries and archives. It calls for greater use of Indigenous research methodologies within library and archival science in order to seek ways to decolonize and simultaneously indiginze libraries and archives. As a written reflection, the article shares the perspectives of the author, who has worked in the sector for the past two decades as an Indigenous Australian archivist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>helmond</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/16/helmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 03:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/16/helmond/</guid>
      <description>In this chapter I provide a historiography of one of the core elements of the web, the hypertext link. I do so with the specific purpose of tracing the various roles of this central web object as a way to understand social, technical and commercial transformations of the web. That is, the hyperlink is positioned as a way to historicize larger web developments and as an alternative way to periodize the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bannon-bardzell-bodker</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/5/bannon-bardzell-bodker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 22:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/5/bannon-bardzell-bodker/</guid>
      <description>Another opportunity is for PD to engage the more overtly political approaches to design that have emerged in HCI in recent years: Feminist HCI, postcolonial computing, and participatory action research all come to mind. Each of these foregrounds social conflict as a condition of computing, and each features sophisticated theories of power, participation, and intervention. Yet none of them have as yet been developed specifically as design methodologies.
In the special issue, Shaowen Bardzell proposes that political approaches to HCI and PD can support each other: Political theory can strengthen PD’s commitments to engaging social conflict, while PD offers mature design methods, often lacking in feminist and postcolonial theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>koster</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/127/koster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 09:13:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/127/koster/</guid>
      <description>We deem it necessary for collections to be FAIR. When collections do not meet the FAIR criteria, these collections will be harder to use by teachers, researchers and enterprises. Collections that will not be FAIR will run the risk of being out of the picture, as will in the long term their institution. The objective of this article is to provide a compact, and practical list of guidelines for achieving reusability of LAM collections that can be fairly easily applied by LAM institutions according to their own roadmaps and resources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intersectional-design</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/125/intersectional-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 14:05:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/125/intersectional-design/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gregory-data-magick</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/102/gregory-data-magick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 14:36:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/102/gregory-data-magick/</guid>
      <description>While it is true that cards “speak” through the symbols or signs that they carry, we can also look to what cards can “do” or what can be “done with” cards, and we can see that a card is not entirely meaningless outside of a semiotic context. Cards, most basically, can be flipped. They can also be used, as Ian Hacking (1988) has shown, as agents of randomization, and simple playing cards were not only employed in the history of the search for telepathy, but cards as an “organizational system” (Hayles 2005, Chun 2005) played an important role in the history of computing, making possible serial functions and memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>organizing-software</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/organizing-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 10:42:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/organizing-software/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sfmoma</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/sfmoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 10:40:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/sfmoma/</guid>
      <description>Undertaken while the museum is closed for a transformational expansion, SFMOMA Lab is conducting a series of explorations into key questions of contemporary museumhood. As part of research focused on digital storytelling, we’re investigating how museums (and their GLAM peers) communicate internally, interinstitutionally, and, in particular, with their many audiences. We’re also interested in how an institution’s professed mission, brand identity, and culture — its philosophy — help shape the various communications, engagements, and experiences it provides for its audiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>olieman</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/olieman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 16:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/olieman/</guid>
      <description>Via Ryan Shaw&amp;rsquo;s presentation at nlp4arc 2018.
 A heightened interest in the presence of the past has given rise to the new field of memory studies, but there is a lack of search and research tools to support studying how and why the past is evoked in diachronic discourses. Searching for temporal references is not straightforward. It entails bridging the gap between conceptually-based information needs on one side, and term-based inverted indexes on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kuipers-military-funding</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/kuipers-military-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 04:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/kuipers-military-funding/</guid>
      <description> My stand is a testimony, saying &amp;ldquo;I will not devote my life&amp;rsquo;s work toward making warfare more effective.&amp;rdquo; I am also trying to show, by example, that one can be a successful and productive computer scientist, even while taking this stand.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>standards-divisions</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/standards-divisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/standards-divisions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>schulte-usds</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/schulte-usds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/schulte-usds/</guid>
      <description>This article tracks the culture of start-ups as it entered government through the U.S. Digital Service (USDS), a new agency and self-described White House “start-up” designed to rewrite the government’s digital presence. This critical discourse analysis traces the cultural history of the start-up, showing how and why it became an American ideal and icon of American power. This explains how and why the start-up became a cultural infrastructure for the federal government and how it became a commonsense solution to both technological and civic problems and a model for “venture government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fasttext-classification</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/23/fasttext-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 19:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/23/fasttext-classification/</guid>
      <description>This paper explores a simple and efficient baseline for text classification. Our experiments show that our fast text classifier fastText is often on par with deep learning classifiers in terms of accuracy, and many orders of magnitude faster for training and evaluation. We can train fastText on more than one billion words in less than ten minutes using a standard multicore CPU, and classify half a million sentences among 312K classes in less than a minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>manning-neurodiversity</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/manning-neurodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 07:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/manning-neurodiversity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>