<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ead on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/ead/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ead on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 21:05:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/ead/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Must Contextual Description Be Bound To Records Description?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/must-contextual-description-be-bound-to-records-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 21:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/must-contextual-description-be-bound-to-records-description/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been struggling with the fact that (American) archival practice seems to bind contextual description (i.e., description of records creators) to records description. Much of these thoughts have been stirring in my head as a result of my class at Rare Book School. If we take a relatively hardline approach, e.g. the kind suggested by Chris Hurley (&#34;contextual data should be developed independently of the perceived uses to which it will be put&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Summer Camp for Archivists&#34; Sounds So Much Better</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/summer-camp-for-archivists-sounds-so-much-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 17:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/summer-camp-for-archivists-sounds-so-much-better/</guid>
      <description>Crossposted to NYPL Labs.
I&#39;m staying with colleagues and good friends during my week-long stint in Charlottesville, Virginia for Rare Book School. If you&#39;re here - particularly if you&#39;re in my class (Daniel Pitti&#39;s Designing Archival Description Systems) - let me know. I&#39;m looking forward to a heady week dealing with descriptive standards, knowledge representation, and as always, doing my best to sell the archives world on Linked Data. Notes and thoughts will follow, as always, on here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dEAD Reckoning #2: Mixing/Matching With Namespaces and Application Profiles</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/dead-reckoning-#2-mixing/matching-with-namespaces-and-application-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 14:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/dead-reckoning-#2-mixing/matching-with-namespaces-and-application-profiles/</guid>
      <description>{% include youtube.html id=&#34;DVbHYRgCtjY&#34; %}
So, it&#39;s time for another rant about my issues with EAD. This one is a pretty straightforward and short one, and comes down to the issue that I should essentially be able to mix and match metadata schemas. This is not a new idea, and I&#39;m tired of the archives community treating it like it is one. Application profiles, as they are called, allow us to define a structured way to combine elements from different schemas, prevent addition of new and arbitrary elements, and tighten existing standards for particular use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dEAD Reckoning #1: A FaTHEADed Failure For Faceted Terms and Headings in EAD</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/dead-reckoning-#1-a-fatheaded-failure-for-faceted-terms-and-headings-in-ead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 01:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/dead-reckoning-#1-a-fatheaded-failure-for-faceted-terms-and-headings-in-ead/</guid>
      <description>A while back, I wrote a Bad MARC Rant, and I considered titling this a Bad Metadata Rant. However, as the kids say, I got mad beef with a little metadata standard called Encoded Archival Description. Accordingly, I figured I should begin a new series of posts discussing some of these issues that I have with something that is, for better or for worse, a technological fixture of our profession. This is in part prompted by thoughts that I&#39;ve had as a result of participating in EAD@10 and attending the Something New for Something Old conference sponsored by the PACSCL Consortial Survey Initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>