<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAA2011 on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAA2011 on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 12:50:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Hack SAA</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/how-to-hack-saa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 12:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/how-to-hack-saa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://declan.net/&#34;&gt;Declan Fleming&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.code4lib.org/index.php/How_to_hack_code4lib&#34;&gt;How to Hack Code4lib,&lt;/a&gt;&#34; I have been motivated to put together a guide to surviving and enjoying the Annual Meeting. It can be a seemingly scary (and potentially lonely) experience if it&#39;s your first conference, and we archivists are not always known for our extrovertedness. So, without further ado, here is my brief list of suggestions - again, some of which have been shamelessly &lt;del&gt;stolen&lt;/del&gt; adapted from Declan&#39;s guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweeting Up at SAA2011</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/tweeting-up-at-saa2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 10:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/tweeting-up-at-saa2011/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the great work of Lance (@newmsi), Rachel Donahue (@sheepeeh), and Angelique Richardson (@RandomArchivist) last year, the first SAA Tweetup was pulled off successfully in Washington, DC. Given that this year&#39;s SAA Annual Meeting is just a few weeks away, Hillel Arnold (@helrond) and I have elected to organize one in Chicago, as well.
We&#39;re holding this year&#39;s Tweetup on Thursday, August 25, starting at 9 PM, at the Clark Street Ale House, which is about a mile from the conference hotel and easily walkable and accessible by public transportation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Hyatt Workers and UNITE HERE Local 1 at the 2011 Annual Meeting of SAA</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2011/supporting-hyatt-workers-and-unite-here-local-1-at-the-2011-annual-meeting-of-saa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 16:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2011/supporting-hyatt-workers-and-unite-here-local-1-at-the-2011-annual-meeting-of-saa/</guid>
      <description>Some of us archivists have growing concerns regarding the long-standing labor dispute between UNITE HERE Local 1 and the management of the Hyatt Regency Chicago, the location of the 2011 Annual Meeting of the Society of American Archivists. Most recently, this labor dispute has led to a one-day strike of housekeepers, dishwashers, bellmen and other hotel workers on June 20, 2011.
SAA has not given its membership any guidance to its membership about how to support UNITE HERE Local 1 and the Hyatt&#39;s hotel workers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>