<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAA2006 on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2006/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAA2006 on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 16:46:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2006/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syndicating archives blogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/syndicating-archives-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 16:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/syndicating-archives-blogs/</guid>
      <description>I still haven&#39;t had enough time to process everything I took in or ideas I came up with as a result of the SAA conference. Many were more diligent than I and I&#39;m sorry to say I didn&#39;t meet them, but some highlights follow:
 Geof Huth took notes on the SAA Awards Ceremony, Christie Peterson pitted Archon against Archivist&#39;s Toolkit, Jessamyn West blogged about her session on blogs, Peter Van Garderen discusses his experience at the conference including his session on archives and Web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report from SAA: Give Me Free WiFi</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/report-from-saa-give-me-free-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 11:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/report-from-saa-give-me-free-wifi/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m at the Hilton Washington, the site of the SAA conference. I&#39;ve registered and picked up my free totebag. I, and others, have bemoaned the lack of connectivity in the conference area. Wireless is only available in the lobby, so it seems, and it&#39;s rather pricy ($5.95 for 4 hours or $9.95 for 24 hours). I know archivists are often thought of as being technologically behind (whether we are is a Pandora&#39;s box that I won&#39;t open in this post), but I feel that some sort of net access is necessary at every conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Time</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/conference-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 01:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/conference-time/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m one of several bloggers attending the SAA conference the rest of this week. Nothing against CoSA or NAGARA, but I&#39;m attending the conference for the organization to which I belong. My schedule is pretty packed, and if you&#39;re one of us be sure to attend the Description Section meeting since I&#39;m running for Vice-Chair.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>