<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAA on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/saa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAA on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 09:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/saa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments on revisions to SAA statement on Diversity and Inclusion</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2020/comments-on-revisions-to-saa-statement-on-diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2020/comments-on-revisions-to-saa-statement-on-diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title=&#34;Society of American Archivists&#34;&gt;SAA&lt;/abbr&gt; Council has issued a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.archivists.org/news/2020/call-for-member-comments-saa-statement-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion&#34;&gt;call for comments&lt;/a&gt; on the SAA Statement on Diversity and Inclusion. As noted in the announcement, the revision includes changes to expand the statement to cover equity as well. Comments are open on the revisions until March 12, 2020, and what follows are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.archivists.org/news/2020/call-for-member-comments-saa-statement-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion#comment-540&#34;&gt;comments that I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Nominations for Co-Chair, RLG Programs Roundtable</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/seeking-nominations-for-co-chair-rlg-programs-roundtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 19:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/seeking-nominations-for-co-chair-rlg-programs-roundtable/</guid>
      <description>Apologies for any duplication - we&#39;re just trying to get the word out!
As co-chairs of the RLG Programs Roundtable of the Society of American Archivists, we&#39;re seeking nominees to co-chair of the Roundtable for 2009-2011. If you&#39;d like to nominate yourself or someone else, please email Mark Matienzo, Co-Chair, at mark at matienzo.org. Please submit all nominations no later than 5 PM Eastern Time on Friday, August 7.
Serving in a leadership position for a Section or Roundtable is a great way to learn about SAA and its governance, contribute to new directions for the Society, and work with other archivists on interesting projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Me A Structured Vocabulary Or I&#39;ll Make One For You</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/make-me-a-structured-vocabulary-or-ill-make-one-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 23:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/make-me-a-structured-vocabulary-or-ill-make-one-for-you/</guid>
      <description>The Society of American Archivists released the Thesaurus for Use in College and University Archives as an electronic publication this week. Specifically, it was issued as a series of PDF files. Is this data stored in some sort of structured format somewhere? If so, it&#39;s not available directly from the SAA site. There&#39;s no good reason why TUCUA shouldn&#39;t be converted to structured, linkable data, expressed using SKOS, the Simple Knowledge Organization System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does SAA Need To Support Who I Am?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/does-saa-need-to-support-who-i-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 22:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/does-saa-need-to-support-who-i-am/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s been a whole lot of discussion in the archivoblogosphere about the perceived need for quasi-informal interest groups that are fundamentally driven by identity. While I agree with this in theory, I must register my opposition to having SAA promote, support, or provide any sort of infrastructure for such groups. Fundamentally, I am against this because I believe it poses a strong threat to the privacy of archivists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to SAA Council and the 2009 Program Committee</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/an-open-letter-to-saa-council-and-the-2009-program-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 12:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/an-open-letter-to-saa-council-and-the-2009-program-committee/</guid>
      <description>I apologize for using my blog to soapbox, but I felt like this was a significant concern that I should share with my readers. If you wish to support my position, please consider sending an e-mail to SAA Council and the 2009 Program Committee Chairs.
Dear 2009 Program Committee Members and SAA Council Members,
I understand that we are nearing the deadlines for submission of proposals for sessions at the 2009 Annual Meeting of the Society of American Archivists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matienzo, The San Francisco Treat</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/matienzo-the-san-francisco-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 17:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/matienzo-the-san-francisco-treat/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m packing up and heading out to SFO this evening for SAA2008. Right now I&#39;m frantically backing up my Zotero repository, making sure I have a bunch of sources to peruse on the plane as I hack away on my slides for EAD@10. You might be surprised that my idea of me jumping out of a cake in the shape of an &amp;lt;archdesc&amp;gt; tag wearing a bathing suit was not even considered, so it looks like I&#39;ll actually have to put some coherent thoughts together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>