<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018: a year in gratitude</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/2018-a-year-in-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/2018-a-year-in-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year was largely complicated and often felt like a massive garbage fire to myself and my crew. I didn&amp;rsquo;t accomplish a number of my goals and was &lt;a href=&#34;https://matienzo.org/2018/iterative-intentions-for-2018/&#34;&gt;inconsistent about others&lt;/a&gt;, so recapping awesome things I did doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel appropriate and also happens to be a soft reminder of either failure or things not going as planned. I also tend to hate &amp;ldquo;best of the year&amp;rdquo; lists but I find them helpful to remember about where I found joy or the ability to connect to something outside of myself. I suppose this is an attempt to reconcile those things, or perhaps more in line with the end of year spirit, a way to articulate gratitude to the people and things around me that impacted me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What one says and does not say: vulnerability, leadership, and professional trajectories</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/what-one-says-and-does-not-say-vulnerability-leadership-and-professional-trajectories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 09:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/what-one-says-and-does-not-say-vulnerability-leadership-and-professional-trajectories/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t say this lightly: participating in ITLP has been transformative for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot through the readings, workshops, and applied learning aspects, but honestly, the most valuable aspects have been individual development and participation in a leadership community. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure why these two things go hand in hand for me, but I believe that it has something to do with the support I&amp;rsquo;ve felt from all of everyone, both the instructors and cohort participants, throughout the program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>