<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAA2007 on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2007/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAA2007 on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 18:28:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2007/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust in the Wind(y City)</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/dust-in-the-windy-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 18:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/dust-in-the-windy-city/</guid>
      <description>SAA2007 came and went. Everyone knows that I&#39;m no good at liveblogging or semi-liveblogging, so don&#39;t expect an exhaustive report - potentially better sources include ArchivesNext and Spellbound Blog. Here are my personal highlights, which is just about the best that this here boy archivist can pull off.
 The pre-conference SAA Research Forum. While I only got to see the second half of the day, this is where the meat was according to those who were there for the whole thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey Chicago</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/hey-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 13:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/hey-chicago/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m in the Windy City for SAA2007. I&#39;ll be pretty busy the first few days in town, but remember, if you want to find me, just look for the glasses. Also, make sure you come to the Description Section meeting and Session 503 on Friday!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAA 2007 Session Proposal: The Changing Nature of Description and OPACs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/saa-2007-session-proposal-the-changing-nature-of-description-and-opacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 00:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/saa-2007-session-proposal-the-changing-nature-of-description-and-opacs/</guid>
      <description>During the Description Section meeting at this year&#39;s SAA conference, I made an informal proposal for a session concerning the changing nature of OPACs, changes in the library cataloging world, and the impact of those on descriptive practice in archives and manuscript repositories. I&#39;d like to invite any of you, if you&#39;re interested, to let me know if you&#39;d be interested in assisting me with putting together a proposal on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>