<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cataloging on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/cataloging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cataloging on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2009 03:45:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/cataloging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is All I&#39;m Going To Say On This Here Blogsite Concerning The Brouhaha About The Policy for Use and Transfer of WorldCat Records Because I Have Other, More Interesting And More Complex Problems To Solve (And So Do You)</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/this-is-all-im-going-to-say-on-this-here-blogsite-concerning-the-brouhaha-about-the-policy-for-use-and-transfer-of-worldcat-records-because-i-have-other-more-interesting-and-more-complex-problems-to-solve-and-so-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2009 03:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/this-is-all-im-going-to-say-on-this-here-blogsite-concerning-the-brouhaha-about-the-policy-for-use-and-transfer-of-worldcat-records-because-i-have-other-more-interesting-and-more-complex-problems-to-solve-and-so-do-you/</guid>
      <description>The moderated discussion hosted and sponsored by Nylink went pretty well. Also, I don&#39;t need the records to have fun with the data &#34;” I just need robust APIs. (In fact, as I said today, I&#39;d prefer not to have to deal with the MARC records directly.) Robust APIs would help making prototypes like this one I hacked together in a few hours into a real, usable service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad MARC Rant #1: Leader Positions 06 and 08</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/bad-marc-rant-#1-leader-positions-06-and-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 13:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/bad-marc-rant-#1-leader-positions-06-and-08/</guid>
      <description>I understand why the MARC leader position 08 is a good idea in theory. In fact, MARBI Proposal 97-07 suggests:
a change in definition to Leader/08 code &#34;a&#34; for clarification; making code &#34;t&#34; (Manuscript language materials) obsolete in Leader/06 and using code &#34;a&#34; instead; redefinitions of codes &#34;a&#34; and &#34;p&#34; in Leader/06; renaming the 008 for Books to &#34;Textual (Nonserial); and deleting field 006 for Mixed material.
 I can safely say that some pretty funky stuff gets cataloged with the leader position 08 set as &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Life Hands You MARC, make pymarc</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/when-life-hands-you-marc-make-pymarc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 18:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/when-life-hands-you-marc-make-pymarc/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s a bad pun, but what can you expect from someone who neglects his blogs as much as I do?
I&#39;ve been busy, somewhat, and one of my latest forays has been getting a grip on Python, an absolutely wonderful programming language. I actually enjoy writing code again, which is more than a bit scary. I was sick of the mangled scripts and workflows I came up with at MPOW to handle converting MARC data to HTML and other such nonsense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Open Data the Point?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/is-open-data-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/is-open-data-the-point/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been thinking about the biblioblogosphere&#39;s reaction to Casey Bisson&#39;s decision to use the $50,000 he was awarded by the Mellon Foundation for his work on WPopac to purchase LC bibliographic data and open it up to anyone who wanted to take a crack at it. Yes, this is a &#34;Good Thing,&#34; and valuable to the library community as a whole, but I feel like there are some things we&#39;re overlooking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RLG &#43; OCLC = Clog Roc?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/rlg-oclc-clog-roc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 16:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/rlg-oclc-clog-roc/</guid>
      <description>The technical services world has been in an uproar lately, between LC&#39;s decision to stop creating series authority records (particularly since they didn&#39;t consult PCC members beforehand) and the fallout after Calhoun report. We might as well have another drink, because as librarian.net reports (along with several others), OCLC and RLG are about to merge. It&#39;s mindblowing to think that RLG employees did not find out any sooner than the rest of us, and that either organization has yet to consult its members.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>