<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code4lib on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/code4lib/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code4lib on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/code4lib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What DPLA and DLF Can Learn from Code4lib</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2015/what-dpla-and-dlf-can-learn-from-code4lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2015/what-dpla-and-dlf-can-learn-from-code4lib/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post has been crossposted to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.diglib.org/archives/7938&#34;&gt;Digital Library Federation blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code4lib.org/conference/2015&#34;&gt;Code4lib 2015&lt;/a&gt; was held last week from February 9-12, 2015 in Portland, Oregon. The Code4lib conferences have grown in the last ten years, both in terms of size and scope of topics. This growth is particularly impressive when you consider that much of the work of organizing the conference falls upon a circulating group of volunteers, with additional organizational support from organizations like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.diglib.org/&#34;&gt;Digital Library Federation&lt;/a&gt;. It has become clear to me that the Code4lib community is interested in ensuring that it can develop and support compelling and useful conferences for everyone who chooses to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go FOAF Yourself</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/go-foaf-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 01:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/go-foaf-yourself/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m really looking forward to next week&#39;s code4lib conference in Providence, despite my utter failure to complete or implement the project on which I am presenting. In particular, I&#39;m really looking forward to the linked data preconference. Like some of my other fellow attendees, I&#39;ve hammered out a FOAF file for the preconference already so that Ed Summers&#39; combo FOAF crawler and attendee info web app.

This is what the sample output looks using my FOAF data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idle Hands Are The Devil&#39;s Plaything</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/idle-hands-are-the-devils-plaything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 01:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/idle-hands-are-the-devils-plaything/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve had my hands full lately. Two weeks ago I was at the MCN conference (wherein, among other things, I have continued my dominion as Archduke of Archival Description by taking over the MCN Standards SIG chair position from The Bancroft Library&#39;s Mary Elings), and next week I&#39;m off to Philadelphia for the PACSCL Something New for Something Old conference. I hammered out the coherent, written version of my paper I gave at EAD@10.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>