<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ArchivesBlogs on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/archivesblogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ArchivesBlogs on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 20:28:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/archivesblogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of ArchivesBlogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2010/the-future-of-archivesblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 20:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2010/the-future-of-archivesblogs/</guid>
      <description>Every project has it&#39;s day. I&#39;ve administered ArchivesBlogs for four years now. Originally, I created it to fill a void when blogging was new to the archival profession, and archivists were having to make the case for dedicating staff time to shepherding early social media projects. Four years later, things are much different; I&#39;m less interested in Web 2.0 (professionally speaking), more archivists are blogging, and more repositories are maintaining their own blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs 3.0</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/archivesblogs-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 01:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/archivesblogs-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Jeanne from Spellbound Blog, I was made aware of the fact that ArchivesBlogs hadn&#39;t really been doing its job. So, I ripped out its guts and put it back together. It&#39;s running the latest, shiniest versions of WordPress, FeedWordPress, and Auto Delete Posts, and now it has added Feedburner and WP Stats goodness. Let me know if you discover any peculiarities in the updated set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Excuses To The Power of Infinity</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/no-excuses-to-the-power-of-infinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 19:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/no-excuses-to-the-power-of-infinity/</guid>
      <description>I have no excuses for not updating this blog. I thought about forcing myself to comply some sort of resolution - you know, given the new year and all - but everyone knows how those turn out. Regardless, I have a whole backlog of things to post about, most notably being the countless Python programming projects I&#39;ve been working on lately. Expect more posts to arise over the next few days as a result of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs Upgrades &amp; Related Weirdness</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/archivesblogs-upgrades-related-weirdness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 17:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/archivesblogs-upgrades-related-weirdness/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve updated ArchivesBlogs to the latest version of WordPress, as well as the latest versions of the plugins that do the heavy lifting (FeedWordPress and Auto Delete Posts). In so doing, I found that the database structure of WordPress 2.3 is radically different, causing some of my elegant work to break (namely, the use of the Auto Delete Posts plugin, for which I wrote a patch). You may have seen duplicate posts, no new posts on specific feeds (language and blog type), and possibly other unpredicted outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday ArchivesBlogs!</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/happy-birthday-archivesblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 18:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/happy-birthday-archivesblogs/</guid>
      <description>It was one year ago today that I made ArchivesBlogs available to the public. Time sure seems to fly by fast! Since then there have been a lot of changes - layout, platform, and hosting - but still, I remain involved for the long haul. Thanks to all who provided suggestions, submitted blogs to be syndicated, and any other guidance along the way. ArchivesBlogs now syndicates nearly 100 blogs in 9 languages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible ArchivesBlogs Downtime: Software Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/possible-archivesblogs-downtime-software-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 12:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/possible-archivesblogs-downtime-software-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>I finally noticed that FeedWordPress, the plugin I use to maintain ArchivesBlogs, has been updated within the last month to work with WordPress 2.1 and higher. I hope to get this working pretty soon, but I apologize in advance if it ends up going down for a few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs On The Move</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/archivesblogs-on-the-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 23:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/archivesblogs-on-the-move/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the wonderful people at ibiblio, ArchivesBlogs will be changing hosts! If you&#39;re not familiar with ibiblio, it&#39;s one of the largest and oldest public digital library collections on the Internet. In addition to the upcoming hosting of ArchivesBlogs, ibiblio also hosts librarian.net and Library Web. Pardon any interruptions in access given the impending move; everything should be settled within a few days.
Also, a few changes I&#39;ve made to the backend should fix most of the continuing issues with certain feeds not aggregating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs Revamped</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/archivesblogs-revamped/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 03:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/archivesblogs-revamped/</guid>
      <description>After many late nights toiling away, I&#39;m done with the latest version of ArchivesBlogs. I&#39;ve changed things quite a bit - most notably, I&#39;ve switched platforms from Plagger to Wordpress using the FeedWordpress plugin to do the heavy lifting of syndication. I&#39;ve decided to do away with the old OPML structure as well since the taxonomy wasn&#39;t as refined as I would have liked. Instead, FeedWordpress can categorize posts as they come in, which has allowed me to create a brand new taxonomy for ArchivesBlogs based on language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs 2.0</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 21:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-2.0/</guid>
      <description>After doing some frantic hacking this week I&#39;m happy to announce that I&#39;ve unveiled the second major revision to ArchivesBlogs. Other than a change in color, I have added the subscription list in the sidebar using a slightly modified version of Dan McTough&#39;s Optimal browser for OPML.The OPML file it renders is also the subscription list used by Plagger. Anyhow, let me know what you think. I&#39;m sure there are some kinks that need to be ironed out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On what &#34;archives blogs&#34; are and what ArchivesBlogs is not</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/on-what-archives-blogs-are-and-what-archivesblogs-is-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 11:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/on-what-archives-blogs-are-and-what-archivesblogs-is-not/</guid>
      <description>I had fully earmarked addressing Thomas G. Lannon&#39;s &#34;Archive Blogs&#34; post on Documenting Sources, his blog, for over a week now after discovering it in my requisite vanity search of Technorati. Other things (even reading) have kept me busy, though, hence the unintentional neglect. I&#39;ve had plenty of time to reflect upon it at this point, so I might as well respond to some of his points.
He first asks the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon: ArchivesBlogs 2.0?</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/coming-soon-archivesblogs-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 16:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/coming-soon-archivesblogs-2.0/</guid>
      <description>After two weeks of use, Plagger has proven itself to be pretty resilient. I&#39;ve been asking myself how I can make ArchivesBlogs even better, and I&#39;ve finally got a few ideas.
 A site redesign. I&#39;d like different colors. Categorizing the feeds, e.g. separating blogs by individuals from repository blogs. This will probably end up with me creating a couple of Plagger configurations and dumping them into different subdirectories on ArchivesBlogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs news: Disappearing Blogspot Blogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-news-disappearing-blogspot-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-news-disappearing-blogspot-blogs/</guid>
      <description>ArchivesBlogs has been going strong for over a week now. If you use Blogspot and had a blog previously syndicated by ArchivesBlogs, your content may be temporarily unsyndicated. The specific problem is HTTP 502 error, which seems to indicate a problem with a proxy server at Blogspot. In any rate, they should return soon enough -- it would be nice to have the 9 blogs back!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchivesBlogs update: service links</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-update-service-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2006 16:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/archivesblogs-update-service-links/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve upgraded Plagger (the software behind ArchivesBlogs) to the latest version and it&#39;s allowed me to add service links to del.icio.us, unalog, digg, Reddit, and Technorati. I suppose I could add more (ma.gnolia, Furl, etc.), but I&#39;ll hold off doing that for the sake of cluttering the interface for the time being. If you have any service links you&#39;d like to see, let me know and I might be able to hack something together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ArchivesBlogs</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2006/announcing-archivesblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2006 10:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2006/announcing-archivesblogs/</guid>
      <description>Since my last post about syndicating blogs about archives, I&#39;ve played around with the idea and different software packages to do it, including Planet and Plagger. I&#39;m happy to announce that after a few days work I was able to put something together.
ArchivesBlogs is an aggregator for blogs about archives. It runs Plagger and updates hourly, outputting HTML, RSS, Atom, OPML (for import into other aggregator), and a FOAFroll. The site design is simple, but i&#39;m happy with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>