<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 15:40:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>letterpress cassette packaging</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2020/135/letterpress-cassette-packaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 15:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2020/135/letterpress-cassette-packaging/</guid>
      <description>a list of presses that produce letterpress printing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nou</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/102/nou/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 15:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/102/nou/</guid>
      <description>As Tim recalls, NOU were in Memphis on tour with Bikini Kill in early 1992 to find that the promoter hadn’t actually promoted their show. So the band immediately took to flyering the streets of Memphis. While walking the streets and going into record stores and whatnot, they ran into Primal Scream who were in town recording an album. At their show that night at the Antenna Club, Primal Scream showed up (being 2 of the 5 paying people at the club) and then after the show, invited NOU to come to the studio to record some songs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>regional-chinese</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/34/regional-chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 22:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/34/regional-chinese/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thorpe</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/24/thorpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 17:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/24/thorpe/</guid>
      <description>This article explores questions regarding the development and support of Indigenous priorities and self-determination in Australian libraries and archives. It calls for greater use of Indigenous research methodologies within library and archival science in order to seek ways to decolonize and simultaneously indiginze libraries and archives. As a written reflection, the article shares the perspectives of the author, who has worked in the sector for the past two decades as an Indigenous Australian archivist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>helmond</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/16/helmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 03:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/16/helmond/</guid>
      <description>In this chapter I provide a historiography of one of the core elements of the web, the hypertext link. I do so with the specific purpose of tracing the various roles of this central web object as a way to understand social, technical and commercial transformations of the web. That is, the hyperlink is positioned as a way to historicize larger web developments and as an alternative way to periodize the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bannon-bardzell-bodker</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2019/5/bannon-bardzell-bodker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 22:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2019/5/bannon-bardzell-bodker/</guid>
      <description>Another opportunity is for PD to engage the more overtly political approaches to design that have emerged in HCI in recent years: Feminist HCI, postcolonial computing, and participatory action research all come to mind. Each of these foregrounds social conflict as a condition of computing, and each features sophisticated theories of power, participation, and intervention. Yet none of them have as yet been developed specifically as design methodologies.
In the special issue, Shaowen Bardzell proposes that political approaches to HCI and PD can support each other: Political theory can strengthen PD’s commitments to engaging social conflict, while PD offers mature design methods, often lacking in feminist and postcolonial theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leon-thinking-with-linked-data</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/334/leon-thinking-with-linked-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/334/leon-thinking-with-linked-data/</guid>
      <description>Given these limitations, historians need to work hard to prevent the data model itself from becoming a site of distortion and misrepresentation that wrongly projects a false degree of stability and permanence. For example, in the community I am studying, information about partner relations between adults comes in many forms. There are few clearly documented sacramental marriages, but many couples are listed together as parents of children, and others are discussed in terms of family units in ledgers and correspondence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>manion</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/332/manion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 13:18:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/332/manion/</guid>
      <description>But the real reason we need to rethink the place of pronouns in public life is even more significant: the advancement of transgender rights. What a distraction the pronoun go-round has become. I have sat through countless meetings in all kinds of spaces facilitated by well-intended people, often gay, sometimes straight, seldom trans, who righteously assert compulsory pronoun identification on everyone in the room and then never speak another word about transgender issues, rights, or people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ucla-community-archives-lab</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/288/ucla-community-archives-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 13:48:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/288/ucla-community-archives-lab/</guid>
      <description> The Community Archives Lab at UCLA explores the ways that independent, identity-based memory organizations document, shape, and provide access to the histories of minoritized communities, with a particular emphasis on understanding their affective, political, and artistic impact.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zina-saro-wiwa</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/258/zina-saro-wiwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 09:17:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/258/zina-saro-wiwa/</guid>
      <description>Another reason indigenous environmentalism is overshadowed I think is because of Pentecostal religion, which has altered Africa’s relationship with the natural world and dampened this connection. Animism, for all its faults as a belief system, described and forged strong relationships between humans and the natural world. For me a Niger Delta environmentalism has to implicate invisible ecosystems, such as spiritual and religious beliefs. We also have to face our own capitalistic desires and manage them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sfbay</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/207/sfbay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 18:42:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/207/sfbay/</guid>
      <description>A massive wetlands-restoration effort aims to protect wildlife, people, and real estate from the worst effects of climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>four-thieves-vinegar</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/207/four-thieves-vinegar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 18:15:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/207/four-thieves-vinegar/</guid>
      <description>For instance, Laufer said that many of the medicines for orphan diseases are made of biological material, such as fungus. &amp;hellip; Since biological cells are self-replicating, this would simply require one user to grow a sufficient amount of cells for themselves before shipping some cells to another user who would repeat the process, similar to the way people ‘seed’ a media file on torrent sites.
The question, then, would be how to ship the biological material cheaply and without getting caught.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>boot-boyz-biz-cixous72</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/200/boot-boyz-biz-cixous72/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 14:17:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/200/boot-boyz-biz-cixous72/</guid>
      <description>How do you invite people to slow down and spend more time investigating phenomena important to our time? Can we turn closets into libraries which reflect important ideas into a public sphere? Can garments be effective as living mobile archives on cotton? We want to consider the idea of ‘looking back to where we’ve come from to understand where we are now and where we’re heading’, and make it a practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>beyond-the-viewer</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/172/beyond-the-viewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 09:18:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/172/beyond-the-viewer/</guid>
      <description>What we also want to do is freely reuse the IIIF model itself, to describe things in manifests without publishing a new manifest for a conventional viewer to load. And then using these extracts, these collected descriptions, to generate new user experiences. The IIIF model is fantastic for this.
All these millions of published IIIF manifests don’t just exist to be processed by viewers. We can cut up the model in different ways, we can say new things by making new IIIF resource fragments as part of a content editorial process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mamaleek</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/163/mamaleek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 10:59:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/163/mamaleek/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bet-shlimon</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/129/bet-shlimon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 09:47:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/129/bet-shlimon/</guid>
      <description>Kirk H. Sowell, a consultant who publishes the risk newsletter Inside Iraqi Politics (for which Al-Tamimi is a contributor), initiated an exchange with me in response to a defense of the NYT’s Iraqi critics that I had written on Twitter. He opened with a tweet reading, “Point me to the Iraqi newspaper which does in-depth investigative journalism &amp;amp; I’ll happily read it.” Puzzled by the relevance of this comment to a statement about the ethics of removing archives for private ownership, I asked Sowell, “Just to be clear: your take is that Iraqis should stay quiet about their archives being taken to the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>koster</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/127/koster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 09:13:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/127/koster/</guid>
      <description>We deem it necessary for collections to be FAIR. When collections do not meet the FAIR criteria, these collections will be harder to use by teachers, researchers and enterprises. Collections that will not be FAIR will run the risk of being out of the picture, as will in the long term their institution. The objective of this article is to provide a compact, and practical list of guidelines for achieving reusability of LAM collections that can be fairly easily applied by LAM institutions according to their own roadmaps and resources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intersectional-design</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/125/intersectional-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 14:05:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/125/intersectional-design/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>winchester</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/104/winchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 12:43:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/104/winchester/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:35:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/103/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:27:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/103/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gregory-data-magick</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/102/gregory-data-magick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 14:36:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/102/gregory-data-magick/</guid>
      <description>While it is true that cards “speak” through the symbols or signs that they carry, we can also look to what cards can “do” or what can be “done with” cards, and we can see that a card is not entirely meaningless outside of a semiotic context. Cards, most basically, can be flipped. They can also be used, as Ian Hacking (1988) has shown, as agents of randomization, and simple playing cards were not only employed in the history of the search for telepathy, but cards as an “organizational system” (Hayles 2005, Chun 2005) played an important role in the history of computing, making possible serial functions and memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molnar</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/101/molnar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 22:31:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/101/molnar/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is still present, but it&amp;rsquo;s shrinking. Content people really care about, customised looking homepages, carefully curated photo galleries are all diminishing. It would be fantastic to return to a world of personal websites, but that needs the love and work that used to be put into them, just like 20 years ago.
At this point in time, most people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to relate to their online content. It&amp;rsquo;s expendable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 20:15:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/101/</guid>
      <description>just testing again&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 20:01:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/101/</guid>
      <description>testing a Workflow/Working Copy note posting workflow on my iPad</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>organizing-software</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/organizing-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 10:42:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/organizing-software/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sfmoma</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/sfmoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 10:40:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/sfmoma/</guid>
      <description>Undertaken while the museum is closed for a transformational expansion, SFMOMA Lab is conducting a series of explorations into key questions of contemporary museumhood. As part of research focused on digital storytelling, we’re investigating how museums (and their GLAM peers) communicate internally, interinstitutionally, and, in particular, with their many audiences. We’re also interested in how an institution’s professed mission, brand identity, and culture — its philosophy — help shape the various communications, engagements, and experiences it provides for its audiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>galligan</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/galligan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 10:06:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/96/galligan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>elhalaby</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/94/elhalaby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 19:33:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/94/elhalaby/</guid>
      <description>The printed matter of the modern Arab or Indian or Chinese mind was simply the bearer of sedition and rebellion or a vehicle for propaganda and profit, never an arena of theory or thinking. Therefore, to write a new history of these ideas, a new archive must be raised. How to raise this new archive, much of it now decaying in Third World libraries that are themselves crumbling under the conditions of structural readjustment or withering away thanks to a growing chauvinist disregard for particular pasts, is the task before us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>diversity-sw</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/94/diversity-sw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 15:08:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/94/diversity-sw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bossk</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/71/bossk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:35:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/71/bossk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>haram</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/59/haram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/59/haram/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>yellow-eyes</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/53/yellow-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 19:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/53/yellow-eyes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spark</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/44/spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 15:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/44/spark/</guid>
      <description>sparkinthedark workshop at code4lib 2018{:.h-event}: understanding the metaphor of data processing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sloan</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/42/sloan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 20:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/42/sloan/</guid>
      <description> just some time is all i need to turn it around  put me on a postcard mail me back home
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>olieman</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/olieman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 16:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/olieman/</guid>
      <description>Via Ryan Shaw&amp;rsquo;s presentation at nlp4arc 2018.
 A heightened interest in the presence of the past has given rise to the new field of memory studies, but there is a lack of search and research tools to support studying how and why the past is evoked in diachronic discourses. Searching for temporal references is not straightforward. It entails bridging the gap between conceptually-based information needs on one side, and term-based inverted indexes on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kuipers-military-funding</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/kuipers-military-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 04:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/33/kuipers-military-funding/</guid>
      <description> My stand is a testimony, saying &amp;ldquo;I will not devote my life&amp;rsquo;s work toward making warfare more effective.&amp;rdquo; I am also trying to show, by example, that one can be a successful and productive computer scientist, even while taking this stand.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>standards-divisions</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/standards-divisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/standards-divisions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>schulte-usds</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/schulte-usds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/26/schulte-usds/</guid>
      <description>This article tracks the culture of start-ups as it entered government through the U.S. Digital Service (USDS), a new agency and self-described White House “start-up” designed to rewrite the government’s digital presence. This critical discourse analysis traces the cultural history of the start-up, showing how and why it became an American ideal and icon of American power. This explains how and why the start-up became a cultural infrastructure for the federal government and how it became a commonsense solution to both technological and civic problems and a model for “venture government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hwc-webmention-cupcakes</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/25/hwc-webmention-cupcakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 03:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/25/hwc-webmention-cupcakes/</guid>
      <description>{:.u-photo}
webmention cupcakes with tantek in the background at Homebrew Website Club SF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fasttext-classification</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/23/fasttext-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 19:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/23/fasttext-classification/</guid>
      <description>This paper explores a simple and efficient baseline for text classification. Our experiments show that our fast text classifier fastText is often on par with deep learning classifiers in terms of accuracy, and many orders of magnitude faster for training and evaluation. We can train fastText on more than one billion words in less than ten minutes using a standard multicore CPU, and classify half a million sentences among 312K classes in less than a minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hwc-2018-01-24</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/21/hwc-2018-01-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/21/hwc-2018-01-24/</guid>
      <description>yes{:.p-rsvp}, i&amp;rsquo;m going to the Homebrew Website Club SF on January 24{:.u-in-reply-to}!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>too-much-music</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/16/too-much-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 17:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/16/too-much-music/</guid>
      <description>And then one day, a revelation: It occurred to me that it was no longer just difficult to hear all the music I&amp;rsquo;d amassed, but impossible. I mean literally, mathematically impossible: I calculated that if I lived another, say, 40 years, and spent every minute of those next 40 years — that&amp;rsquo;s no sleeping, no eating — listening to my collection of music, I would be dead before I could make it all the way through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goldin-opioid</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/goldin-opioid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 08:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/goldin-opioid/</guid>
      <description>I SURVIVED THE OPIOID CRISIS. I narrowly escaped. I went from the darkness and ran full speed into The World. I was isolated, but I realized I wasn’t alone. When I got out of treatment I became absorbed in reports of addicts dropping dead from my drug, OxyContin.
I learned that the Sackler family, whose name I knew from museums and galleries, were responsible for the epidemic. This family formulated, marketed, and distributed OxyContin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>manning-neurodiversity</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/manning-neurodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 07:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/manning-neurodiversity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iiif-resources</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/iiif-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 07:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/10/iiif-resources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 23:35:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>critical-algorithm-studies</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/critical-algorithm-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 20:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/critical-algorithm-studies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>adapdesk</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/adapdesk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 20:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/adapdesk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>posner-infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/posner-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 08:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/posner-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>beehive</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/beehive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 01:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/beehive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netlify-push</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/netlify-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 01:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/8/netlify-push/</guid>
      <description>this is an experiment to use a netlify deploy notification (an outgoing webhook) to notify a PuSH hub. the bits are wired together using beehive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moro-cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/moro-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/moro-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netlify-cms-workaround</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/netlify-cms-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 03:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/netlify-cms-workaround/</guid>
      <description>{:class=&amp;quot;u-photo&amp;rdquo;}
a silly workaround was to use a field named title that has a label of &amp;ldquo;Slug&amp;rdquo; in the netlify-cms config, which then allows you to avoid filename collisions until https://github.com/netlify/netlify-cms/issues/445 is fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netlify-cms-mobile</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/6/netlify-cms-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 09:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/6/netlify-cms-mobile/</guid>
      <description>netlify cms posting on mobile is doable but not great. the editor pages are not responsive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netlify-cms</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/6/netlify-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 07:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/6/netlify-cms/</guid>
      <description>test of netlify cms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 16:07:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quake</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/4/quake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 15:22:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/4/quake/</guid>
      <description>i felt my first earthquake. while i was up late last night working on my website. a magnitude 4.4 earthquake{:.u-url .p-name}. its origin was 2km SE of Berkeley, CA (37.855{:class=&amp;quot;p-latitude&amp;rdquo;}, -122.257{:class=&amp;quot;p-longitude&amp;rdquo;}) at 2018-01-04 10:39:37.730 UTC. this is was also an excuse to work more on my website, adding bookmarks and locations to posts, and experimenting with marking up an h-event in the text of a post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2018/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 16:21:03 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2018/3/</guid>
      <description>procrastinating on doing my reading for itlp</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>