<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAA2009 on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2009/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAA2009 on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 07:31:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/saa2009/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything is Bigger in Texas, Including My Talks on The Semantic Web</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/everything-is-bigger-in-texas-including-my-talks-on-the-semantic-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 07:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/everything-is-bigger-in-texas-including-my-talks-on-the-semantic-web/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ll be at the Society of American Archivists Annual Meeting next week in Austin, Texas. It looks to be a jam-packed week for me, with a full-day Standards Committee/TSDS meeting on Tuesday, followed by THATCamp Austin in the evening, an (expanded version of my) presentation on Linked Data and Archival Description during the EAD Roundtable on Wednesday, and Thursday&#39;s session (number 101): &#34;Building, Managing, and Participating in Online Communities: Avoiding Culture Shock Online&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to SAA Council and the 2009 Program Committee</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2008/an-open-letter-to-saa-council-and-the-2009-program-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 12:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2008/an-open-letter-to-saa-council-and-the-2009-program-committee/</guid>
      <description>I apologize for using my blog to soapbox, but I felt like this was a significant concern that I should share with my readers. If you wish to support my position, please consider sending an e-mail to SAA Council and the 2009 Program Committee Chairs.
Dear 2009 Program Committee Members and SAA Council Members,
I understand that we are nearing the deadlines for submission of proposals for sessions at the 2009 Annual Meeting of the Society of American Archivists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>