<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digitization on Mark A. Matienzo</title>
    <link>https://matienzo.org/tags/digitization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digitization on Mark A. Matienzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 08:54:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matienzo.org/tags/digitization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AIP Receives NHPRC Funding To Digitize Samuel Goudsmit Papers</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2009/aip-receives-nhprc-funding-to-digitize-samuel-goudsmit-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 08:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2009/aip-receives-nhprc-funding-to-digitize-samuel-goudsmit-papers/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy to pass on the news that my former employer, the Niels Bohr Library &amp;amp; Archives of the American Institute of Physics, has received funding from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission to digitize the entirety of the Samuel Goudsmit papers. From the announcement on the Center for History of Physics/Niels Bohr Library &amp;amp; Archives Facebook page:
Goudsmit (1902—1978) was a Dutch-educated physicist who spent his career in the US and was involved at the cutting edge of physics for over 50 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Work-Safe Tidbits about Archives and Erotica</title>
      <link>https://matienzo.org/2007/two-work-safe-tidbits-about-archives-and-erotica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 14:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matienzo.org/2007/two-work-safe-tidbits-about-archives-and-erotica/</guid>
      <description>First, via my associates at booktruck.org, I came across a review of the comic book Demonslayer v. 2.2, by a certain Marat Mychaels, et al. at Comics Should Be Good. While the fact that the reviewers pan the comic book seems only marginally of interest to those of us wading in archivy, I should draw your attention to a specific part of this issue. Apparently one of the characters goes to visit the Director of Archives at the New York Museum of Natural History, who has chosen to decorate his office in the style of some seemingly life-sized works by (fellow Peruvian) Boris Vallejo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>